如果箱子上没有标签，莫妮卡会生气的
Oh,you know,Monica's gonna freak if every box isn't labeled.
好…一箱…
You're right,yeah. Okay..
垃圾
"Box of crap."
莫妮卡和钱德回来时会带个孩子
It's so wild. When Monica and Chandler come back,they are gonna have a baby.
-孩子！ -我知道
- A baby! - I know.
哦，罗斯还不知道
Wait. Ross doesn't know the baby's coming.
打个电话给他吗？
Should we call and tell him?
我不知道 瑞秋还在那冲他喊叫
I don't know. Rachel's still there yelling at him.
可怜的家伙.我现在可真不想成为他啊
Poor guy. I would not wanna be him right now.
等一下，我们该这样吗？
Wait. Wait. Should we be doing this?
不知道
I don't know.
-说不定是个好主意 -也许不是
- It's probably not a really good idea. - Yeah,probably not.
-我们以前从来没停止过 -是啊
- Well,that never stopped us before. - No,sir!
大结局
The.Last.One
不敢相信几小时后我们就成父母了
I can't believe we're gonna be parents soon.
不能相信已经三个星期了
I can't believe it's three weeks early.
我爱我们的孩子这么迅速
I love that our baby is prompt.
刚才护士说艾瑞卡在哪儿？
Okay. All right,what room did the nurse say Erica was in?
- 702. - 哦
- 702. - Okay.
-来吧，宝贝 -来吧，你能行
- Come on,baby. - Come on. You can do this.
快把那个鬼东西从我里面弄出来！
Get this damn thing out of me!
这是给你们的
Well,these are for you.
你看见那女人出来的东西有多大吗？
Did you see the size of the thing that was coming out of that woman?
我都不知道谁在生谁
I couldn't tell who was giving birth to who.
-嗨 -嗨，怎么样了？
- Hi. - Hey. How's it going?
很好，医生说还要一会儿
It's okay. The doctor says it'll still be a while.
-感觉怎样？ -有时候疼
- How do you feel? - Well,it hurts sometimes.
不过不厉害。我有点害怕
Not too bad yet,though. It's a little scary.
我知道，没事的
Oh,I know. But,honey,you're gonna be fine.
告诉她那个702房生孩子的女人
Tell that to the lady in 702 with the toddler coming out of her.
我想那个孩子是穿着衣服的
I think that kid was wearing a shirt.
你会没事的
You're gonna be fine,though.
嗨~
Hey.
接着睡吧，我该回家了
Go back to sleep. I have to go home.
真是太棒了
Oh,God. This was amazing.
的确是太棒了
It really was.
你学了不少新招儿嘛
You've learned some new moves.
同事给了我一本《菜鸟性爱指南》想取笑我的
Yeah,well,this guy at work gave me Sex for Dummies as a joke.
-现在看谁笑到最后了 -没错
- Who's laughing now? - I am.
呼气、呼气、呼气
Breathe. Breathe. Breathe.
这样就对了
Okay. Good.
下次我说呼气行吗？
Next time,can I say "breathe"?
不行，刚才你说得像吸血鬼一样，吓死她了。
No. Last time,you said it like Dracula,and it scared her.
还要点东西吗？冰片？
Do you want some more ice chips?
-没事，不用了 -我马上就回来
- No,I'm okay. - All right. I'll be right back.
-去哪里？ -洗手间啊
- Where you going? - To use the bathroom.
-别把我们俩丢在一起啊 -什么？
- You can't leave me alone with her. - What?
这是个很重要的场合
This is exactly the kind of social situation..
我最怕的就是这种场合了
that I am not comfortable with.
什么样的场合你不怕啊！
What kind of social situation are you comfortable with?
我和她从来没单独待在一起过
It's just that we've never spent any time,you know,alone together.
没事的…才怪。不过我马上就回来了
You'll be fine. You won't,but I'll be back in two minutes.
哦
Okay.
那个…夏天有什么打算？
So any plans for the summer?
不清楚，可能参加个教会野营吧
I don't know. Maybe church camp.
哈…我为啥非要提这个
May not want to mention this.
有没有想过哪种情况更糟？
So you ever wonder which is worse?
产前阵痛和蛋蛋被踢？
You know,going through labor or getting kicked in the nuts?
-说什么？ -就是想想挺有意思的。
- What? - Oh,it's just interesting.
谁也不会知道的，因为没人两种情况都能经历吧。
Because no one will ever know because no one can experience both.
这是关于生命的难以置信的问题之一
One of life's great unanswerable questions.
谁知道，也许还有比那两种情况更糟糕的呢！
Who knows? Maybe there's something even more painful than those things.
比如现在
Like this.
-请进 -早啊
- Come in. - Morning.
-嗨！ -什么呀？！
- Hey. - What's that?
送莫妮卡和钱德的乔迁之礼
Oh,it's my housewarming present for Monica and Chandler.
刚出生的小鸡和小鸭！
That's a baby chick and duck.
我给它俩取名叫小小鸡和小小鸭
And I named them Chick Jr. and Duck Jr.
真的是没想到哈
I did not see that coming.
那么大的后院它俩肯定会喜欢的
They'll love it at that new house. It has that big backyard.
以后要是老了的话 钱德可以和上次一样把它们送到
When they're old,they'll go to that farm..
上次那个农场去
that Chandler took the other chick and duck to.
-没错 -是啊
- Yes. - Yeah.
-不过不能去看望实在是太不爽了 -没办法，规矩就是这样
- It's a shame people can't visit there. - That is the rule though.
-好消息！你马上就要当舅舅了！ -什么？
- Guess what. You're almost an uncle. - What?
艾瑞卡马上要生了 莫妮和钱德现在正在医院呢
Erica went into labor. Monica and Chandler are at the hospital right now.
-天哪！ -我敢肯定是个女孩
- Oh,my God! - I have a feeling it's gonna be a girl.
你原来还猜本是个女孩来着呢
Phoebe,you were sure Ben was gonna be a girl.
从没看过他踢球吧？
Have you seen him throw a ball?
-瑞秋在不在？ -还在睡觉吧
- Is Rachel here? - I think she's still asleep.
嗨！昨晚你俩怎么样了，她好像怒了
How did it go with you guys last night? She seemed pretty pissed at you.
啊…后来事情解决了
We worked things out.
笑啥呢？你俩是不是有点什么事？
What's that smile? Did something happen with you two?
我不会亲了不说
Hey,I'm not one to kiss and tell.
也不会做爱了再闭嘴。我们什么都做了
But I'm also not one to have sex and shut up. We totally did it.
天啊，你和瑞秋？
Oh,my God. You and Rachel?
-是啊，感觉太棒了 -意味着什么啊？
- I know,it's pretty great. - So,what does that mean?
-你们复合了？ -说不好
- Are you guys getting back together? - Oh,I don't know.
-我俩还没仔细谈过 -你自己想复合吗？
- We didn't really get to talk. - But do you want to get back together?
不清楚啊…
I don't know.
真的是难以置信，再合适不过了
It was incredible. I mean,it just felt so right.
我把她抱在怀里时，永远都不想让她离开。
When I was holding her,I mean,I never wanted to let her go.
嗯…没错，我想和她在一起
Know what? Yeah,I do. I want to be together.
那她还去巴黎吗？
So is she still going to Paris?
还没想过，希望不会吧
Wow,I hadn't thought of that. I hope not.
今天太伟大了、太伟大了！ 你俩要复合
This is,like,the best day ever. Ever. You guys might get back together.
莫妮卡和钱德要有小孩 而且…
Monica and Chandler get their baby. There are chicks and ducks..
世界上又有小鸡小鸭了！
in the world again.
啊~！感觉就像在音乐剧中一样！
I feel like I'm in a musical.
-早啊！ -永远也唱不完整了…
- Morning. - Guess you'll never know how it ends.
- 嘿 - 嗨！
- Hey. - Hi.
-睡得怎样？ -很好，你呢？
- Hi. How'd you sleep? - Good. You?
-不错 -那还用说
- Good. - I'll bet you did.
啊…能让我俩单独待会儿吗？
Would you guys mind giving us a minute?
好，帮忙看着点小鸡和小鸭
Sure. Just keep an eye on the chick and duck.
小鸡和小鸭？不是已经死…
Chick and the duck? Didn't they die..?
死活非要去农场哦
Dive. Yeah,they dove. Headfirst into fun on the farm.
所以…
So..
-早啊 -你也是啊
- Morning. - You too.
-昨晚太棒了 -真的是
- Last night was just wonderful. - Oh,it really was.
-我今天醒来满脸都是笑容
I woke up today with the biggest smile.
-我也是啊
I know,me too. It was..
就像…有些事情觉得从来不可能
You know,it was one of those things you think is never going to happen.
但有一天真的发生了 而且是自己所希望的那样
And then it does,and it's everything you want it to be.
我知道，实在是…
I know. It was just..
实在是最好的告别方式了
It's just the perfect way to say goodbye.
-再努力一点！ -疼死我了！
- Just a little bit more,honey. - Oh,man,this hurts!
真疼得那么厉害？
Is it really that bad?
现在该踢你蛋蛋了，看看哪个更疼！
I think it's time to kick you in the nuts and see which is worse.
婴儿的头已经要出来了
The baby's head is crowning.
天哪！我所见过的最美丽的头顶了！
Oh,my God! That is the most beautiful top of a head I have ever seen.
-钱德！过来看！ -我就不用了
- Chandler,you have to see this. - I'm okay.
钱德！绝不能错过的！ 你孩子出生了！
You don't want to miss this. This is the birth of your child.
-生命的奇迹啊！ -好吧
- It's the miracle of life. - All right.
哇！这么恶心的奇迹！
Wow,that is one disgusting miracle.
开始往外挤
Start pushing. Here we go.
好！肩膀出来了！
Here come the shoulders.
是个男孩！
It's a boy.
-他不要紧吧？！ -不要紧的
- Is he okay? - He's just fine.
你成功了！
You did it.
婴儿！
It's a baby.
美丽的小婴儿！ 还有点其他东西我就装没看见吧！
A beautiful little baby. And some other stuff I'm gonna pretend I don't see.
-准备好切脐带了吗？ - 好了
- Would you like to cut the umbilical cord? - Okay.
居然还一跳一跳的！
Well,that's spongy.
嘿！帅哥
Hey,handsome.
我爱死你了！谁家的女孩儿都配不上你！
I'll love you so much that no woman is ever gonna be good enough for you.
-咱们太幸运了！ - 是啊
- We are so lucky. - I know.
他眼睛和你的一样
He has your eyes.
虽然不可能吧，不过真的是
I mean,I know that's not possible,but he does.
把他擦干净些
We'll just get him cleaned up a bit.
真是太美了
Oh,my God,he's beautiful.
-多谢你啊 -太为你们俩高兴了
- Thank you so much. - I'm really happy for you guys.
-现在感觉如何？ -很累
- How do you feel? - I'm tired.
没多少时间可歇了，下一个马上就出来。
You don't have that much time to relax. The other one will be along in a minute.
抱歉…谁要出来？刚才你说啥？！
I'm sorry,who should be along in a what,now?
下一个孩子马上就出来
The next baby should be along in a minute.
我们只订了一个！
We only ordered one.
-你们知道是双胞胎吧？ -才怪
- You know it's twins,right? - Oh,yeah.
知道的话我们俩还能这副表情？
These are the faces of two people in the know.
怎么可能不知道是双胞胎？ 以前从来没有过的
I can't believe you didn't know it's twins. This has never happened before.
啊！我现在感觉还真特别爽啊
Well,gosh. That makes me feel so special and good.
等等，你知道是双胞胎？
Did you know it was twins?
是啊，门诊送过来的文件里面写着呢
It's here in the paperwork we got from the clinic.
-有人告诉过你吗？ -没有啊
- Did anybody tell you? - I don't think so.
不过确实提到了两种心跳 我当时觉得应该就是我和孩子的吧
They did mention two heartbeats,but I thought it was just mine and the baby's.
他们就一直说两个心跳都很强
They said,"Both heartbeats are strong."
我就觉得 不错啊，因为我正怀着孩子哪
And I thought,"Well,that's good,because I'm having a baby."
-太难以置信了 -我家有双胞胎的传统的
- This is unbelievable. - Twins actually run in my family.
真有意思哈
Interesting.
跟你谈点事
Can I see you for a second?
-现在咋办？ -什么咋办？
- What do we do? - What do you mean,"What do we do?"
双胞胎！
Twins!
-钱德！你在发抖 -没错！和我一起抖吧！
- Chandler,you're panicking. - Join me,won't you?
我们留一个，另一个给别人如何?
What do you say we keep one and then just have an option on the other one?
-怎么可以分开啊！ -怎么不行啊！
- We can't split them up. - Why not?
给他俩一人半块信物
We could give each of them half a medallion.
数年之后他们凭着信物重逢
And then years later,they'll find each other..
大团圆！ 到那时候大家该多开心啊
and be reunited. I mean,that's a great day for everybody.
如果领养另一个人的是坏蛋呢？
What if the person who adopts the other one is horrible?
要不是呢？要是被某国王领养了呢？
What if they're not? What if it's adopted by a king?
是哈，听说国王要领养个孩子！
Yeah. Because I hear the king is looking to adopt.
莫妮卡，咱俩没想好要两个孩子的
Monica,we are not ready to have two babies.
又有什么关系！ 咱们等了这么久
That doesn't matter. We have waited so long for this.
我才不管是一个孩子还是两个孩子！ 仨孩子都没关系！
I don't care if it's two babies. I don't care if it's three babies.
生出《八宝喜事》全剧组来都没关系！
I don't care if the entire cast of Eight Is Enough comes out of there.
一定要把他们带回家 因为他们是咱们的孩子啊。
We are taking them home because they are our children.
好吧
Okay.
- 好 - 好
- Okay. - Okay!
好了
Okay.
看来我们这里准备好了!来吧,艾瑞卡.
It looks like we're about ready over here. Come on,Erica.
现在,再推一次吧
Start pushing again now.
-女婴也出来了！ -女婴？！是个女孩？！
- Here she comes. - She? It's a girl?
对
Yeah.
现在一男一女了！
Well,now we have one of each.
然后就别再生了！
And that's enough.
后来她说那个是最好的告别方式
And then she said it was the perfect way to say goodbye.
天哪，你说什么了？
Oh,my God. What did you say?
-什么都没说。能说什么啊？ -罗斯！一定要告诉她你的感受啊！
- Nothing. What do you say to that? - You've got to tell her how you feel.
-不行！ -不能就这么放弃她啊！
- No way. - Well,you can't just give up.
恐龙会这么做吗？
Is that what a dinosaur would do?
-什么？ -我就是想用你们的语言和你说
- What? - I'm just trying to speak your language.
瑞秋不知道你想复合
Ross,Rachel doesn't know that you even wanna get back together.
如果她知道 想法可能就会变啊，也许就不会走了
If she did,she might feel differently. She might not even go.
-真的？ -没错的。
- You really think so? - I'm telling you!
啊！如果是音乐剧的话，现在就应该是高潮了。
Oh,this is the part of the musical where there'd be a good,convincing song.
-嗨！ -就不能让一个女孩把歌唱完吗
- Hi. - Can't a girl finish a song around here?
-嘿 -刚把艾玛交给我妈了
- Hey. - Hi. I dropped Emma off at my mom's.
-哦 -你今晚不带艾玛走？
- Okay. - You're not taking her tonight?
不带了，我先去整理好 我妈星期天把艾玛带去
We decided I'd set up,then my mom would bring Emma to Paris on Sunday.
哇！陪一岁小孩飞八个小时？祝你妈妈好运
Eight-hour flight with a baby. Good luck,Mom.
开玩笑，听我妈唠叨八个小时的阿特金斯减肥法？ 祝艾玛好运
You kidding? Eight hours with my mom talking about Atkins. Good luck,Emma.
你说得对，至少要告诉她我的感受
All right. You know what? You're right. I should at least tell her how I feel.
-罗斯等一下！ -什么？什么？
- Ross. Wait,wait. - What? What?
给我带个松饼吧
Could you get me a muffin?
-瑞秋？ -嗯？
- Rachel? - Yeah?
我知道你今晚就走了 我就是想告诉你…
I know you're leaving tonight,but I just have to tell you.
我爱你
I love you.
不知道你的计划会不会因此改变…
Now,I don't know if that changes your plans at all.
不过我觉得还是应该告诉你
But I thought you should know.
甘瑟！
Gunther.
我也爱你 不过和你爱我含义应该不一样
I love you too. Probably not in the same way.
但我真的爱你 每次我在咖啡屋喝咖啡
But I do. And when I'm in a cafe having coffee..
或者看见谁的头发比太阳还亮
or I see a man with hair brighter than the sun..
我都会想起你
I'll think of you.
-回头见 -再见~
- Bye,you guys. - Bye.
天哪！
Oh,my God!
难以置信啊
Unbelievable.
-我有个好主意… -我不会给你拿松饼的！
- Hey,you know what might help? - I'm not getting you a muffin!
你觉得他俩从肚子里出来，认得出对方吗？
Do you think they recognize each other from in there?
也许，不过也可能像俩多年的邻居
Maybe. Unless they're like people who've lived in apartments..
突然有一天被挤出产道
next to each other for years,then one day they're pushed through a vagina..
终于见面了
and they meet.
我们现在带艾瑞卡去休息了
We're going to take Erica to Recovery now.
有点事情我们要和你说
There's something that we wanted to tell you.
我们决定给女孩起名为艾瑞卡
We decided to name the girl baby Erica.
天哪！这不和我名字一样吗？！
Oh,my God,that's just like my name!
他妈的绝对是啊
Son of a gun,it is.
总之我要先去休息了
Anyway,I'm gonna go get some rest.
能选中你们俩我太高兴了 你们俩一定会成为好父母的
I'm really glad I picked you guys. You're gonna make great parents.
甚至连钱德也是
Even Chandler.
-再见 -再见
- Okay,well,bye. - Bye.
-我们会给你打电话的 -好
- We'll call you. - Okay.
教会野营愉快啊！
Have fun at church camp.
-看看这些小家伙 -是啊
- Look at these little bunnies. - I know.
想换换吗？
You ready to trade?
- 好 - 好
- Okay. - Okay.
好，这样
Okay. Let's see.
-一会儿再换吧 -没问题
- We could trade later. - Yeah,I'm good.
-嗨，你在干嘛呢？ -写欢迎标语呢
- Hey,what are you working on? - A "welcome home" sign for the baby.
（欢迎回家，宝宝）真不错啊，那画的是婴儿吗？
How sweet! Oh,is that the baby?
不是…我坐到颜料上了…
No,I sat in the paint.
-嘿 -和瑞秋说了吗？
- Hey. - So did you talk to Rachel?
-没说，也不打算说了 -什么？
- No. And I'm not going to. - What?
-为什么啊 -因为她会拒绝我的
- Why not? - She's just gonna shoot me down.
你俩也看见甘瑟了 最后成那样有意思吗？
You saw what happened with Gunther. That did not look like fun.
你怎么能把自己同甘瑟比？
How can you compare yourself to Gunther?
的确他从表面上来说比你更性感…
I mean,sure,he's sexy in a more obvious way.
你和瑞秋真正做过恋人啊 你们俩昨晚还一起过夜了
You have a relationship with her. You slept together last night.
没错！可是她还是要走！ 很清楚她现在是怎么想的了
Yeah,and she still wants to go. It's pretty clear where she is.
我能理解，有时候…
I know what you mean. I mean,sometimes..
-啊，乔… -妈的！
- Joe. - Damn it!
即使我要和她说，也不用现在吧
If I were gonna tell her,I don't have to do it now.
以后还能见，有的是时间
Okay? I'll be seeing her again. We've got time.
哪儿有？她是要去巴黎啊！ 她会最终和某人定下来的！
No,you don't. She's going to Paris! She is going to meet somebody.
知不知道巴黎有多少帅哥？！ 简直就是甘瑟之城！
Do you know how many hot guys there are in Paris? It's a city of Gunthers.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
-手里拿什么呢？ -做了点东西
- What do you have there? - Oh,I made a little something.
时间充裕本来可以更好的（欢迎来到这个世界，宾宝宝）
If I had more time to work on it,it'd be better,but..
-哇！你自己一个人弄的？ -这也太漂亮了吧亲爱的！
- Oh,my God,you did that yourself? - Honey,that's gorgeous.
婴儿又不识字，麦克！
You know,the baby can't read,Mike.
去机场的车都来了，他们怎么还没回来！
Hi. The car service just got here. I can't believe they're not home yet!
我要赶飞机啊！我要看看孩子！
I have to catch my stupid plane. I want to see the baby.
莫妮卡刚才在车上打电话说马上就到
Monica just called from the cab. She said they should be here any minute.
-而且好像还要有个惊喜？ -她听起来口气高不高兴？
- Apparently,there's some big surprise. - Yeah,did she sound happy about it?
我有个朋友的孩子刚出生就有点胡子
Because my friend Ethel's baby was born with a teeny-tiny beard.
-欢迎回家！ -天哪！
- Welcome home. - Oh,my God.
-天哪！ -嘿
- Oh,my gosh. - Hey.
嘿
Hey.
你说的惊喜是什么啊？
Hey,so,what is the big surprise?
-天呐！ -这个问题…
- Oh,my God! - How did this..?
有点尴尬 不过医院知道你们拿了两个回来是吧？
Okay,awkward question. The hospital knows you took two,right?
-知道，是双胞胎！ -太可爱了啊
- Yes. It's twins. - Oh,my.. They are so cute.
-是男是女？ -这是男孩，那是女孩
- Now,what kinds are they? - This is a boy. And that's a girl.
女孩名叫艾瑞卡。
Her name is Erica.
那个怀孕的女孩不也叫艾瑞卡吗？
Hey,that pregnant girl's name was Erica.
没错…你们俩没多相处相处太可惜了
Yeah. It's a shame you two didn't get to spend more time together.
我们给男孩起名叫杰克，随爸爸的。
Yeah,and we named the boy Jack,after Dad.
-他一定会高兴极了。 -杰克宾…这名字我喜欢！
- He's gonna be so happy. - Jack Bing. I love that.
听起来像是四十年代写新闻的啊。 “杰克宾，早报
It sounds like a '40s newspaper guy. You know,"Jack Bing,Morning Gazette.
看我怎么渲染这条故事的！”
I'm gonna blow this story wide open."
哦，我的天
Oh,my gosh.
-太美了！ -我也想要一个
- So beautiful. - I want one.
哦？告诉我哪个，一会儿夹在大衣里带走
Oh,yeah? Well,tell me which one. I'll try to slip it in my coat.
说真的，不想生一个？
Seriously. I mean,you want to make one of those?
-一个？一堆怎么样？ -真的？
- One? How about a whole bunch? - Really?
是啊。啊！可以教他们唱歌！ 就像《音乐之声》范特普一家一样！
Yeah. We can teach them to sing,and we could be like the von Trapp family.
不过要把纳粹部分删去… 但是这样就没意思了…
Only without the Nazis. Although that sounds kind of dull.
真是让人不爽，不过我要是 再不走就赶不上飞机了
I can't believe this. If I don't leave now,I'm gonna miss my plane.
-你能见孩子们一面我真是太高兴了 -我也是
- I'm so glad you got to see the babies. - Me too.
真遗憾不能留下来看你照顾孩子手忙脚乱了
I'm just sorry I'm not gonna be around to watch you two attempt to handle this.
真的说不出告别的话
All right. Oh,I can't say goodbye to you guys again.
-我太爱你们了 -我也爱你
- I love you all so much. - Love you.
-爱你 -到了打电话啊
- We love you. - Call us when you get there.
一定，罗斯，过来
I will. Ross,come here.
我想告诉你
I just want you to know..
昨晚…
last night..
我永远都不会忘记的
I'll never forget it.
我也不会
Neither will I.
现在真的要走了
All right. Now I really have to go.
Au revoir！（蹩脚的法语“再见”）
Okay,au revoir.
啊…巴黎人一定会恨死我的
They're gonna really hate me over there.
你就这么让她走了？
So you just let her go?
嗯
Yeah.
-这样也许是最好的了 -真的？
- Hey,maybe that's for the best. - Yeah?
真的，关于昨晚
Yeah. You know,you just.. Look,you gotta..
她怎么想 你也应该怎么想
You gotta think about last night the way she does.
也许…也许在一起过夜
Okay? You know,maybe..
就是最好的告别了
Maybe sleeping together was the perfect way to say goodbye.
他们一起睡觉了？
They slept together?
我和你在一起
I was with you.
-可是这样一来她就不知道他的感受了啊 -也许没关系的
- Now she'll never know how he feels. - Maybe that's okay,you know?
也许这样更好。
Maybe it is better this way.
现在…现在你可以向前继续生活了
I mean,now.. Now you can move on.
你已经努力适应这么久了
I mean,you've been trying to for so long.
现在你们俩身在不同的大陆…
Maybe now that you're on different continents..
是吧？
Right?
也许你现在终于可以解脱了
Maybe now you can actually do it,you know.
终于可以不再想她了
You can finally get over her.
的确是这样没错
Yeah,that's true.
可是…
Except..
-我不愿意就这样解脱 -什么？
- I don't want to get over her. - What?
-我不想…我想和她在一起 -真的？
- I don't. I want to be with her. - Really?
-嗯，我去追她 -去吧！
- Yeah. I'm going to go after her. - Yeah,you are!
穿上外衣！穿上外衣！
Wait! Wait! Get your coat! Get your coat!
-外衣… -太酷了！
- My coat. - This is so cool!
虽然一点都不明白咋回事  不过我现在太兴奋了！
I have no idea what's going on,but I am excited!
-罗斯！你觉得她会怎么说？ -不知道！
- What do you think she's gonna say? - I don't know.
不过即便她拒绝我 我也不会余生
Even if she shoots me down,at least I won't spend my life wondering..
都活在猜测之中 我外衣哪儿去了！
what would have happened. Where is my coat?
你根本就没穿来！ 我车就在下面，开车送你去机场！
You didn't bring one! My cab's downstairs. I'll drive you to the airport.
-大伙祝我好运！ -快！
- Wish me luck. - Hurry!
祝你好运
Good luck!
天啊
Oh,my God.
罗斯去追瑞秋，你们有了孩子
Ross is going after Rachel. And you guys have babies.
这就像是最棒的一天！
This is,like,the best day ever!
我沙发上怎么有屁股形状的东西？
Why is there an ass-shaped paint stain on my couch?
是你的问题，麦克！
She asked you a question,Mike.
你真觉得我们能及时赶到?
You really think we'll make it in time?
嘿,我的驾照还没被吊销,因为我开车很小心
Hey,I didn't have my license taken away because I drive carefully.
-没安全带？ -没关系，一旦车撞到什么东西，
- There's no seat belts! - That's okay. If we hit anything..
马达就会爆炸  相比之下还是被甩出去比较好
the engine will explode,so it's better if you're thrown from the car.
-好！我们走！ - 好!
- All right,all right. Let's do this. - Okay!
- 嘿 -东区80号
- Hey! - 80th and East End.
-我不载客 -法律规定逢客必载的！
- No. I don't take passengers. - The law makes you accept any fare.
你不明白，这车本来就不是计程车！
You don't understand. This cab isn't real.
等我去投诉你，你牌照号多少
What's your medallion number?
号码是：滚出车去！
My medallion number is,get out of the cab!
-什么？ -滚出车去！滚出车去！
- What? - Get out of the cab!
嘿！大家看
Hey,you guys. Check this out.
- 不! - 好
- No! - Okay.
哦！现在给你们乔迁之礼怎么样？
Oh,hey,can I give you guys my housewarming gift now?
-可以呀 -好
- Now,that you can do. - All right.
问个问题
I have a question.
如果不看下面你能分清他们吗？
Without looking under their diapers,can you tell them apart?
当然可以，我是妈妈啊
Of course I can,I'm their mother.
好，那个是谁？
Oh,yeah? Okay. Which one is that one?
是杰克
That's Jack.
哇！有阴道的杰克在高中会有麻烦了
Jack's gonna have a tough time in high school with that vagina.
小小鸡？小小鸭？
Chick Jr.? Duck Jr.?
别和妈妈捉迷藏！
Don't hide from Mama!
现在可以睁开眼睛了
You can open your eyes now.
-下桥了吗？ -下了！
- Are we off the bridge? - Yes!
-自行车上的老太太还活着吗？ -活着！她及时跳开了！
- Is the woman on the bicycle still alive? - Yeah,she jumped right back up.
-天哪！菲比！开慢点！ -你到底想不想及时追上瑞秋！
- Oh,my God. Phoebe,slow down! - Do you want to get to Rachel in time?
想！不过我不想死在你车里！
Yes,but I don't want to die in your cab.
上车之前你怎么不想清楚！！！
You should have thought of that before you got in!
-收费站 -什么？
- Tollbooth. - What?
收费站!
Tollbooth!
四块钱，杂物箱里有零钱
Four bucks. There are quarters in the glove compartment.
快点！
Hurry!
哦
Okay.
妈的，窗户怎么这么干净！
Damn,that window's clean.
我们还奇怪拿礼物这么半天还不回来
We were wondering what was taking so long..
现在才知道你在干这个…
but now we understand. You were doing this.
我本想给你们个惊喜的…
Okay. I wanted to surprise you,but..
作为乔迁之礼，送给你们一只小鸡一只小鸭！
For your housewarming gift,I got you a baby chick and a baby duck.
真的？给我们小鸡小鸭？
Really? You got us a chick and a duck?
太好了，家里有婴儿，鸟粪正合适啊！
Oh,great. Just what you want for a new house with infants. Bird feces!
一定是从桌子上跳下去了，现在都不见了啊！
But they must've jumped off the table. Now they're gone!
别着急，慢慢找
Don't worry,we'll find them.
我去看孩子去了
Actually,I'm gonna go check on the twins.
啊!我刚才踩着什么了！
Oh,God! What did I just step on?
没事，就是个蛋卷
It's okay. It's just an egg roll.
你竟敢踩着我的蛋卷！
You stepped on my egg roll?!
抱歉，谁会想到地上会有中国菜！
I'm sorry. I didn't know to look for Chinese food on the floor.
放到盘子里，然后快走
Just put it on a plate and leave.
-好了. 开始找吧 - 好
- Okay. Let's find these birds. - All right.
等等！听到了没？
Wait,wait. You hear that?
-啊！在桌子里！ -这可不妙了！
- They're in the table! - Well,that can't be good.
-必须要取出来！ -怎么取？！
- We gotta get them out of there! - How?
也许能引诱他们出来，你知道鸟怎么叫吗？
Maybe we can lure them out. You know any birdcalls?
当然了，我就是干伐木工的
Oh,tons. I'm quite the woodsman.
把桌子一头抬起来点也许管用
Well,maybe we can just tip the table a little.
乔伊等一下！球还没...
Joey,wait! The ball!
现在怎么办！
So,what do we do?
不清楚…也许边上什么地方能打开吧
Maybe we can open this up somehow.
好
Okay.
不行啊，都粘上了
No. It's all glued together.
也就是说要…撬开？
Does that mean we have to bust it open?
-不知道…也许吧 -天呐！
- I don't know. Maybe. - Oh,my God.
我明白…这可是足球桌啊
I know. It's.. It's the foosball table.
好吧，你知道吗，我们别无选择
All right,you know what? We don't have a choice.
就像一部如果我得到角色的科幻电影里面的台词一样
It's like I would have said in that sci-fi movie if I'd have gotten the part.
“里面有人！必须要救出来！”
Those are our men in there,and we have to get them out..
“即使要牺牲我生命中最重要的东西--
even if I have to sacrifice the most important thing in my life..
我的时间机器…”
my time machine.
-这电影拍出来了没？ -根本也没拍…
- Did that movie ever get made? - It did not.
-罗斯！你去哪里？ -去找瑞秋啊
- Ross,where are you going? - To talk to Rachel.
所以我才坐死亡计程车来的
Isn't that why we took a ride in the death cab?
你就直接去登机口？
You're walking up to her at the gate?
以前没在机场追过人？！
Have you never chased anyone through the airport before?
我的警察戏镜头被取消之后就没有过了…
Not since my cop show got canceled.
必须先买票才能通过安检
You have to get a ticket to get past security.
-那就赶不及了啊！ -保持这种气势！快滚过来！
- What? We're never gonna make it. - Not with that attitude. Now,haul ass!
大家再走慢点就好了
Okay,if you could all walk slower,that'd be great.
- （法式英语）小姐，看一下您的护照？ -天呐！
- Madame,your passport,please. - Oh,my God.
我还害怕高中学的法语都忘干净了呢！
I was afraid I wouldn't remember my high school French.
你刚才说的每个字我都听明白了！
But I understood every word you just said.
-看一下您的登机牌？ - 哦，当然
- Your boarding pass,please. - Oh,sure.
好的…找不到… 本来在啊…真叫人…
Shoot,I had it. Oh,I can't believe this.
-小姐，如果您没有… -我有我有我有我有！
- Madame,if you don't have your.. - I have it,I have it!
哎呀，找不到，不过我清楚记得 我的座位号是32C
Okay,I can't find it,but I remember that I was in seat 32C..
因为跟我的胸罩大小一样。
because that's my bra size.
-小姐，您必须要有登机牌，否则…
You must have your boarding pass..
知道吗，我要是36D，就没这么多麻烦了！
You know what? If I was in 36D,we would not be having this problem.
-您好，我要买一张票 -就买一张？
- Hi. I need a ticket. - Just one?
我开车这么大老远送你过来 不能看看结局啥样？
I drive you here,and I don't get to see how it works out?
-好吧，两张，我买两张票！ -我们在度蜜月
- Fine. Two tickets. I need two tickets. - We're on our honeymoon.
-目的地是？ -随便，最便宜的吧
- And the destination? - I don't care. Whatever's the cheapest.
我嫁给你真是太走运了
I'm so lucky I married you.
啊！倒霉！妈的！哪里去了！
Oh,shoot. Damn it. Where is it?
啊！找到了找到了！哈！ 找到了！早和你说了我有！
I found it. I found it. I told you I would find it.
你是另外一个人了..
In your face. You're a different person.
抱歉
Sorry.
421航班，巴黎
Okay. Flight 421,Paris.
-找不到，你呢？ -我也找不着。错过了？
- I don't see it. Do you see it? - No. Did we miss it?
不可能，20分钟后才起飞的
No,no,it's impossible. It doesn't leave for another 20 minutes.
航班号错了吧
Maybe we have the flight number wrong.
天呐
God.
-嗨 -嗨，是我，这是罗斯
- Hello. - Hey,it's me. Here's Ross.
什么？
What?
嗨！听着…
Hey. Hey,listen..
天啊，孩子的声音太可爱了！罗斯你听！
You wouldn't believe the cute noises the twins are making. Wait,listen.
但是莫妮卡
But Monica..
莫妮卡？…莫妮卡！莫妮卡！…
Monica. Monica. Monica.
抱歉，他俩刚才还出声来着
I'm sorry. They were doing it before.
-莫妮卡！听着… -等等！又来了！！
- That's all right. Listen,listen. - Oh,wait,wait. Here they go again.
莫妮卡！莫妮卡！莫妮卡！莫妮卡！
Monica. Monica. Monica.
- 莫妮卡？ -可爱吧！
- Monica? - Isn't that cute?
可爱死了！听着
That is precious! Listen..
-我要瑞秋的航班信息 - 哦，好
- I need Rachel's flight information. - Oh,okay.
- 421航班，8点40起飞。 -是啊，就是这个，看板上找不到
- All right,it's flight 421. Leaves at 8:40. - I have that. It's not on the board.
这里就是这样写的啊，421航班  8点40起飞，纽瓦克机场
That's what it says here. Flight 421. Leaves at 8:40. Newark Airport.
-什么？ -纽瓦克机场
- What? - Newark Airport.
-怎么了？你们在哪里？ -肯尼迪机场…
- Why? Where are you? - JFK.
别着急！会把你们救出来的！
Don't worry,you guys! We're gonna get you out of there!
然后再给你们买小鸟用的助听器…
And we're also gonna buy you tiny bird hearing aids.
好，来了…
Okay. Here goes.
怎么了？
What's the matter?
我要先跟桌子告别
I need to say goodbye to the table first.
我理解
I understand.
好
Okay.
桌子！
Table..
你曾经给予我们太多的欢乐时光
you have given us so many great times.
你们大伙…乔丹、维克多，还有乔
And you guys,Jordan,Victor,Joel..
你们所有人，我得说
All of you guys. What can I say?
是你们让我俩更有形象
You guys make us look good.
-你想说什么？ -不清楚…
- You want to say anything? - I don't know.
不过，最后一次…
Except that,for one last time..
干得好…干得好…干得好…干得好…
Good game. Good game. Good game.
干得好
Good game.
好吧,来,动手
Okay. Here we go.
我下不了手
I can't do it.
我也下不了手啊！
Well,I can't do it either.
-找到没？ -在桌子里面！
- Hey. Did you find them? - Yeah. They're stuck inside the table.
必须要撬开，不过我们俩都下不去手！
And we have to bust it open,but neither of us can do it.
是啊…太难了…
Oh,well,sure. It's got to be so hard.
我来吧，给我！
I'll do it. Give me.
菲比！
Phoebe!
不要啊！
No,no,no!
以前从没开这么快过！！
Wow,I've never gone this fast before.
菲比！算了吧！纽瓦克 一个小时才能到
Phoebe,forget it,okay? Newark is,like,an hour away.
根本赶不上
There's no way we'll make it in time.
-她拿着手机呢！打电话！ -我不要在电话上谈
- She's got her cell. You could call her. - I am not doing this over the phone.
你没其他办法了啊
You don't have any other choice.
- 喂? -瑞秋？太好了！
- Hello? - Rachel. Oh,good.
顺便问一句，你是不是刚上飞机？
By the way,did you just get on the plane?
-是啊 -如果机场没去错的话
- Yeah. - We would have caught her..
我们能赶上她的
if we were at the right airport.
-瑞秋，等一下 - 不不不
- Rachel,hang on. - No. No. No.
菲比？你那边不要紧吧？
Phoebe,is everything okay?
啊，事实上，有点事情 你必须下飞机
Actually,no. No. You have to get off the plane.
-啊？为什么？ -我有种感觉
- What? Why? - I have this feeling that..
飞机有问题，左“弗兰基”有毛病
something's wrong with it. Something is wrong with the left phalange.
亲爱的，飞机肯定没问题的。
Oh,honey,I'm sure there's nothing wrong with the plane.
马上要起飞了，我爱你 一到巴黎就给你打电话。
Look,I have to go. I love you,and l will call you the minute I get to Paris.
-你刚才说什么？ -哦，我的疯朋友
- What was that? - Oh,that was just my crazy friend.
让我下飞机 因为她就是感觉到
She told me to get off the plane because she had a "feeling" that there..
飞机左“弗兰基”有毛病
was something wrong with the left phalange.
-听起来可不妙吧 -不用担心
- Okay. That doesn't sound good. - Oh,I wouldn't worry about it.
她老是这样，而且几乎从没对过。
She comes up with this stuff,and she's almost never right.
-也就是说她也有对的时候？ -啊
- But she is sometimes. - Well..
-你要干吗？ -这飞机我不能坐
- What are you doing? - I can't take this plane now.
-对不起先生，您去哪里？ -我要下飞机。
- Excuse me,sir. Where are you going? - I have to get off this plane.
她朋友感觉到 飞机左“弗兰基”有毛病
Her friend has a feeling something's wrong with the left phalange.
请给我拿点花生好吗？
Could I get some peanuts?
-飞机怎么了？ -飞机一点异常都没有
- What's wrong with the plane? - There's nothing wrong.
-左“弗兰基”有毛病了 -根本就没有什么“弗兰基”！
- The left phalange. - There's no "phalange."
天哪！这飞机连“弗兰基”都没有！
Oh,my God. This plane doesn't even have a phalange.
-我不飞了 -女士，请您坐好
- I'm not flying on it. - Please sit down.
-出什么事情了？ -我们都下去！飞机上根本就没有“弗兰基”！
- What's going on? - We're getting off. There is no phalange!
太荒谬了吧，我…
This is ridiculous. I..
啊随便吧
Yeah,okay.
好了，工作完成
All right. My job here is done.
太令人钦佩了
That was impressive.
大部分连工具都没用就弄下来了
Yeah. You didn't even use the tools for most of it.
工具只会拖慢我的速度
Yeah,they were just slowing me down.
好啦，我回去看孩子了 你们两个姑娘一会儿见。
All right. I gotta get back to the babies. See you girls later.
-真抱歉，桌子这样了。 -嗯
- Sorry about the table,man. - Yeah.
要买新的吗？
You gonna buy a new one?
也许不了…不会了
Probably not. No.
你走后我估计也不会怎么玩了
I don't know how much I'm gonna want to play after you go.
-至少这两个小家伙救出来了 -是啊
- At least we got these little guys out. - Yeah.
我们还担心你们呢
We were worried about you.
以后要习惯有东西在我手里拉屎的事情了
I guess I better get used to things crapping in my hand,huh?
我会想你们的，小家伙
I'm gonna miss these little guys.
再养养鸟还真挺不错的
It was nice having birds around again.
这样吧，它们就交给你了
Hey,you know what? Maybe we should keep them here with you.
-什么？ -嗯，我们现在也忙得要死
- What? - Yeah. We got a lot going on right now.
而且这里也有它们的房间啊
And plus,here,they'd have their own room.
还可以再养只鹅！
I could get a goose!
我觉得家禽类这两只就够了
You know,I think you're set with the poultry.
多谢了。 听到没有？
Thanks,man. You hear that,you guys?
你们要留在这里啦！ 而且这样也挺好的
You're gonna get to stay here. And it's good..
因为…
you know,because..
你就有理由多回来看看了
Because now you have a reason to come visit.
其实还有一个理由
I think there may be another reason.
那个…
So..
是尴尬的拥抱呢… 还是假酷男握手呢
Awkward hug or lame cool-guy handshake?
还是假酷男握手吧
Yeah,well,you know,lame cool-guy handshake.
-女士，我向您保证，飞机没有问题。 - “弗兰基”也装好啦？
- Ma'am,I assure you,the plane is fine. - And you fixed the phalange?
没错，装好了，而且
Yes. The phalange's fixed.
还又带了一个备用的以防万一
In fact,we've put a whole lot of extra phalanges onboard,just in case.
-她在哪儿？ -看不到
- Where is she? - I don't see her.
-瑞秋！瑞秋格林！-她在那里！
- Rachel! Rachel Green! - There she is!
瑞秋！
Rachel! Rachel!
-先生，您有登机牌吗？ -没有，我就是要找里面的一个人说句话…
- Whoa,do you have a boarding pass? - No. I just have to talk to someone.
对不起，没有登机牌不能再往前走了
I'm sorry. You need a boarding pass.
-不 不… -瑞秋！
- No,no. But you don't.. - Rachel!
什么？上帝啊？你们在这里干嘛呢？
What? Oh,my God. What are you guys doing here?
轮到你了
Okay. You're on.
怎么了？怎么了罗斯？ 你吓到我了，出什么事了？
What? What,Ross? Okay,you're scaring me. What's going on?
- 嗯…我想说的是： - 什么
- Okay. Thing is.. - Yeah.
-不要走 -什么？
- Don't go. - What?
留下来和我在一起，我太爱你了。 求求你不要走
Please,please stay with me. I am so in love with you. Please don't go.
-天哪 -我知道，我知道
- Oh,my God. - I know. I know.
不应该拖到现在才说的 我太笨了，对不起。
I shouldn't have waited till now to say it,but.. That was stupid,okay? I'm sorry.
不过我现在和你说：我爱你
But I'm telling you now. I love you.
-不要上飞机 -小姐？您是否要上飞机？
- Do not get on this plane. - Miss,are you boarding the plane?
嘿
Hey,hey.
我知道你爱我，我知道
I know you love me. I know you do.
-小姐？ -我…
- Miss. - I..
我要上飞机
I.. I have to get on the plane.
-不要，别上飞机 -我要上
- No,you don't. - Yes,I do.
-不要，别上飞机 -都等着我呢，罗斯。
- No,you don't. - I do. They're waiting for me,Ross.
我现在真的不能这么做，对不起 对不起
I can't do this right now,I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
瑞秋
Rachel.
真的对不起
I'm so sorry.
我本来以为她会留下的…
I really thought she'd stay.
我知道
I know.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
那么,就这样了
Well,that's it.
收拾完毕
Everything's packed.
-啊，感觉有点怪啊 -我明白
- This is weird. - I know.
嗯
Yeah.
啊…也就是说没吃的了？
Does this mean there's nothing to eat?
我在你冰箱里面放了三盘意大利面
I put three lasagnas in your freezer.
我爱你
I love you.
- 嘿 -怎样？赶上了吗？
- Hey. - Hey. Did you guys make it in time?
赶上了，他跟她说了 不过她最后还是上了飞机
Yeah,yeah. He talked to her,but she got on the plane anyway.
罗斯呢？
Where's Ross?
回家了，他谁也不想见
He went home. He didn't want to see anybody.
“罗斯，嗨，是我”
Ross. Hi,it's me.
“我刚回到飞机上” “我现在感觉太难受了”
I just got back on the plane,and I just feel awful.
“我绝不希望我们之间这么就完了”
That is so not how I wanted things to end with us.
“只是…只是我根本没料到你会出现”
It's just that I wasn't expecting to see you.
“猛一下子你就来了，还说那些话…”
And all of a sudden you're there and saying these things.
“我现在坐在这里，静静地想…”
Now I'm just sitting here and thinking..
“想我应该说却没有说出口的话”
of all the stuff I should have said and I didn't.
“我甚至都没跟你说我也爱你”
I mean,I didn't even get to tell you that I love you too.
“因为，我真的爱你”
Because of course I do. I love you.
“我爱你”
I love you.
“我到底在干什么？我爱你！”
What am I doing? I love you.
“我要见你，我要下飞机！”
I've got to see you. I've got to get off this plane.
天哪
Oh,my God.
-“打扰一下！” -“小姐，请坐下”
- Okay,excuse me. - Miss,please sit down.
“真对不起，我要立刻下飞机！
No,I'm sorry. I'm really sorry,but I need to get off the plane.
-去告诉他我爱他！” -“小姐，现在不能下飞机”
- I need to tell someone that I love them. - I can't let you off.
让她下飞机！
Let her off the plane!
“请您务必坐好”
You have to take your seat.
“求求你了，你不明白！”
Oh,please,miss. You don't understand.
试着去明白！
Try to understand!
“拜托了，有没有办法让我能下…”
Come on,miss,isn't there any way that you can just let me off the..?
不要！
No! No!
上帝啊，到底下没下飞机？到底下没下飞机？！
Oh,my God. Did she get off the plane? Did she get off the plane?
我下飞机了…
I got off the plane.
你下飞机了…
You got off the plane.
我真的爱你
I do love you.
我也爱你，再也不会让你走了
I love you too,and I am never letting you go again.
我也希望留在这里，再也不要有遗憾
Okay. Because this is where I want to be. No more messing around.
- 我不想再搞砸了 - 我也不想,我们已经蠢过一次了
- I don't want to mess this up again. - Me neither. We're done being stupid.
只有你和我，好不好，  只有你和我
Okay. It's you and me,all right? This is it.
只有你和我 除非我们是在分手中…
This is it. Unless we're on a break.
现在可不是开玩笑的时候
Don't make jokes now.
请小心点，这是我祖母的，
Okay,please be careful with that. It was my grandmother's. Be careful.
请务必小心，多谢
Thank you.
如果这玩意儿从车上掉下去， 也没什么大不了的
If that falls off the truck,it wouldn't be the worst thing.
是啊
I know.
看起来好像小了一圈
Seems smaller somehow.
一直都是紫色的？！
Has it always been purple?
小家伙们，看看四周吧 这里曾是你们的第一个家
Look around,you guys. This was your first home.
一个幸福的家 充满了爱心与欢笑
And it was a happy place,filled with love and laughter.
更重要的是 租金管制简直就是明抢啊
But more important,because of rent control,it was a frigging steal.
嗨，你们有没有意识到， 我们每个人都在这里住过
Hey,do you realize that,at one time or another,we all lived in this apartment?
真的是
Oh,yeah. That's true.
啊…我没有
I haven't.
你大学有一年暑假过来和祖母住
What about that summer during college that you lived with Grandma..
然后你想靠跳舞来挣钱…
and you tried to make it as a dancer?
你有没有意识到，这都十年前的事了你还往外挖？
Do you realize we almost made it 10 years without that coming up?
啊亲爱的，我差点忘了。 我答应崔格把钥匙留下
Oh,honey,I forgot. I promised Treeger that we'd leave our keys.
好
Oh,okay.
-都结束了？ - 是啊
- So I guess this is it. - Yeah.
嗯…应该是吧
I guess so.
比想象中的还要难啊！
This is harder than I thought it would be.
会好的
Oh,it's gonna be okay.
好了
Come on.
你们俩马上要去新房子了，或者能挤出点时间来吗？
Do you guys have to go to the new house now,or do you have some time?
还有点时间
We got some time.
-去喝杯咖啡怎么样？ -好啊。
- Okay. Should we get some coffee? - Sure.
去哪儿喝？
Where?